绿洲汽车旅馆
冰爽礼物
你的美臀真漂亮*
*Que lindo es tu cucu cucu
真的好漂亮*
*Tan bello tu cucu cucu
圆润又松软*
*Redondito y suavecito cucu
你的美臀真漂亮*
*Que lindo es tu cucu cucu
穿上紧身裤*
*Cuando te pones pantalón cucu
自摸你翘臀*
*Y te tocas por de--
别对我的美臀乱来*
*No te metas con mi cucu cucu
我知道你有娇妻*
*Yo se que tienes tu mujer
别对我的美臀乱来*
*No te metas con mi cucu cucu
小伙子都目不转睛*
*Nunca faltan los mirones cucu
就像你和别人那样*
*Como tú y los demas cucu
你想看就看吧*
*Si quieres puedes mirar cucu
想看就看个够*
*No que a ti te de la gana cucu
乱来赏你一耳光*
*Te daré una cachetada cucu
别*
*No --
美臀*
*...cucu cucu
我知道你有娇妻*
*Yo se que tienes tu mujer**Cucu
美臀*
*Cucu
久等了
Thank you for your patience.
你不是说听证会只是走形式而已吗
Didn't you say that the hearing is more or less a formality?
实际工作已经完成了  对
Well, the real work's already been done, yes.
那样的话  我自己应付得来
In that case, ‭I'm fine covering it myself.
凯文和佩奇不需要我俩都去
Kevin and Paige ‭don't need both of us there.
你说得也许很对
That may be strictly true,
但我们想传达正确的信息  是不是
but we want to send the right message, don't we?
我就是担心你不舒服
I'm just worried about your comfort.
庆祝胜利最让我舒服
I find victory laps very comforting.
干得好  朋友
Well-done, my friend.
早上好
Good morning.
现在召开新墨西哥州银监局会议
This meeting of the New Mexico State Banking Board is now in session.
今天来的是梅萨维德银行
We have Mesa Verde here with us today,
由查尔斯·麦吉尔代表
and they're represented by Charles McGill.
真高兴你回来  查尔斯
Nice to have you back, Charles.
谢谢  能回来真好
Thank you. Good to be back.
我和同事霍华德·哈姆林一起
I'm here with my colleague, Howard Hamlin.
我有幸向你们介绍凯文·沃弛泰尔先生
And may I introduce Mr. Kevin Wachtell,
梅萨维德集团总裁兼董事长
President and Chairman of Mesa Verde Holdings,
以及佩奇·诺维克女士
and Ms. Paige Novick,
梅萨维德高级法律顾问
Mesa Verde Senior Counsel.
欢迎你们
Hello and welcome.
工作人员认为
I believe staff has found the application
申请书基本符合通过标准
to meet the basic requirements for approval.
对不对
That's right, isn't it?
如果您允许的话
With your permission,
沃弛泰尔先生想做个简要介绍
Mr. Wachtell would like to make a brief statement
以支持其申请
in support of the application.
专员先生
Mr. Commissioner,
新墨西哥州银监局的女士们先生们
ladies and gentlemen of the New Mexico Banking Board,
我有幸能在今早来到各位面前
I'm honored and grateful to appear before you this morning.
我们认为  我们提出的扩张
We believe ‭that our proposed expansion
符合亚利桑那州和我州的公众利益
is in the public interest both for Arizona and our own state.
四十六年来  梅萨维德银行信托的员工
For 46 years, the men and women of Mesa Verde Bank and Trust
为我们首屈一指的个性化服务和
have prided ourselves on personal service
对细节的执着感到骄傲
and attention to detail second to none.
梅萨维德经营的一级杠杆比率
Mesa Verde continues to operate at a Tier One leverage ratio
保持在11.2%  我们
of 11.2%, and we feel --
等下
Uh, hold on.
抱歉  沃弛泰尔先生  稍等一下
Excuse me, Mr. Wachtell. Just one moment.
怎么了
What's going on?
问一下吧
Well, let's find out.
专员先生  有什么需要我们解释的吗
Uh, Mr. Commissioner, is there something we can clarify?
有
Uh, yes.
能告诉我们拟设的
Can you give us the address
斯科茨代尔支行的地址吗
of the proposed Scottsdale branch again?
当然可以
Certainly.
亚利桑那州斯科茨代尔
It's 1216 Rosella Drive,
罗塞拉路1216号  85262
Scottsdale, Arizona, 85262.
1-2-1-6?
好  我现在看着的申请书
Okay. Because the application I'm looking at today
清清楚楚地写着1216号
clearly gives the address as 1216.
1216  是的  先生
1216 -- that's correct, sir.
但在你们最初提交的文件中
But in the original submission,
写的是罗塞拉路1261号
we're seeing 1261 Rosella Drive.
-是1261  -1261
- It is 1261. ‭- 1261.
如果你们复查一遍  就会发现应该是1216
I think if you double-check, you'll see that 1216 is correct.
似乎是两个不同的地址
There seem to be ‭two different addresses here.
专员先生  我这儿有一份意向通知书复印件
Mr. Commissioner, I have a copy of our notice of intent,
之前发表在亚利桑那和新墨西哥州的报纸上
which was published in newspapers in Arizona and New Mexico.
上面明确写着地址是罗塞拉路1261号
It clearly states the address is 1261 Rosella Drive.
专员先生...
Mr. -- ‭Mr. Commissioner, I-if --
罗塞拉路1261号
1-2-6-1 Rosella Drive.
是的  我这也有一份意向通知书
Yes, I have a copy of the notice of intent, too,
但是正式提交的文件上
but on the actual filing,
地址写的是1216号
the address reads 1-2-1-6.
所以...哪个才对
So...which is it?
专员先生  我能与委托人交换意见吗
Mr. Commissioner, ‭if I may confer with my clients?
没问题  请
Certainly, please.
绝对是1261号
It's absolutely 1261.
你搞错了
You are mistaken,
恕我直言  你这是在添乱
and with all due respect, you're muddying the waters here.
"添乱"
"Muddying the water"?
看
‭Look.
自己看
Just look.
这很明显是个错误
Well, ‭this is clearly an error.
是1261没错
It's 1261.
我当然知道自己的银行在哪
I know where my own damn bank is.
我们都冷静一下
Uh, let's just all calm down.
肯定可以理清楚的
I'm sure we can straighten this out.
我在罗塞拉路1261号改造了一栋楼
I've got a building remodel at 1261 Rosella.
我倒不知道1216号是哪里
I don't know where the hell 1216 is.
我不太明白...  1261
I-I don't quite underst-- 1261.
-是1261  -这有什么问题吗
- 1261. - ‭Is this gonna be a problem?
不会  肯定没问题
No, I'm sure it won't be.
专员先生  抱歉
Um, M-Mr. Commissioner, I apologize.
不知为何  我们的文件里
Unaccountably, there appears to be a...
似乎出现了矛盾
discrepancy in our filing.
所以正确的地址
So the correct address the one
是意向通知书上的1261号吗
that appeared in the notice of intent, the 1261?
看似如此
It would seem so.
我们想请求...
Uh, uh, uh, ‭we'd like to request a, um,
休会几分钟
an adjournment of just a few minutes
好让我们将文件修改为正确的地址
so that we can amend the filing to reflect the correct address.
我可以允许休会
Well, I-I can give you an adjournment, uh, uh,
但是...
but, uh...uh,
今天可能没办法重新听证了
I don't think we can get you back in today.
请问什么时候可以重新安排听证
If I may, when do you think you might be able to schedule us?
工作人员告知
I'm being told by staff
他们已经对罗塞拉路1216号进行了调查
that they've already done the research for 1216 Rosella Drive.
如此一来我们的人又得去新的地址
Our folks are going to have to go back to square one
-从头开始  -如果...
- on the new address. - If we --
如果我们今天能取得一份临时协议
we could obtain a provisional agreement today,
允许分行设立...
to allow the -- the branch to open be--
不  不  恕我直言
No, no. All due respect,
提交准确的文件是你们的责任
it's up to you folks to submit accurate paperwork.
下次最好再次核对
Maybe next time, double-check.
如今  最快能够重新听证的时间
Now, uh, the soonest we could revisit this matter --
应该是六周后的周五
well, it -- it looks like six weeks from Friday.
我们等不了六个星期
We -- ‭We can't wait six weeks.
专员先生  梅萨维德银行已耗费精力与资源
Mr. Commissioner, M-Mesa Verde has put effort and...resources
准备好即刻让分行开张
into preparing this branch to open immediately.
虽然罕有先例  如果能给个临时许可
However unusual, a provisional a-approval
我们会感激不尽
would be most appreciated, most welcome.
时间至关重要...
Time being of the essence --
查尔斯  很抱歉  我们六周后见
Charles, I'm sorry. I'll see you in six weeks.
今天就到此为止
That closes the matter for today.
工作人员请注明
Will staff please note
梅萨维德将于六周后返回
that Mesa Verde will return in six weeks...
届时再重新对该申请听证
...at which time, we will revisit this application?
已经安排好了
That's on the schedule now.
我们会加快进行所有新增调查
And we'll have expedited all the additional research.
不可能
This is not possible.
这不可能
This is not possible!
1261  不可能
1261. No. No.
查克
Chuck. ‭
我不懂
I don't understand.
我不懂  是1216号
I don't understand. It was 1216.
没错的  我检查了一遍
It was. I checked!
又检查一遍
I double-checked!
查克  发生就发生了
Chuck, it happened.
我们接受失败  别再纠结了
Now we take our licks, and we move on.
这不仅仅是你的错
This doesn't just reflect on you --
律所里这么多律师和助理都疏忽了
an office full of associates and paralegals let this get by.
包括我自己
I did, too, for that matter.
是1216号  我保证
It was 1216 -- I promise you.
每个人都会犯错
Everyone makes mistakes.
这可不是犯错
This was no mistake.
希腊甜品屋
我请这儿所有人喝一杯
I'm buying a round for the house.
-真的  -没错
- Yeah? - ‭Yeah.
大伙听好
Hey, listen up, everybody!
这位先生要请所有人喝一杯
This gentleman's buyin a round for the house!
好了  用膝盖的力
All right, lift with your knees
那到底什么意思  "用膝盖的力"
What does that even mean -- "Lift with your knees"?
不知道  汗流浃背的人都这么说  来吧
I don't know. It's something sweaty people say. Here we go.
一  二  三
1, 2, 3.
-好了吗  -差一点
- Got it. - Almost.
快了  快了  快了  快了
Almost, almost, almost, almost.
-好了吗  -好了
- Got it? ‭- All right.
好了  就这儿  放手  放手
Oh, right there. Go. Go.
你还好吧
You okay?
做几年的理疗肯定能治好
Nothin a few years ‭of physical therapy won't fix.
-好  -好  推
- ‭Okay. - All right. Push.
慢点  慢点  慢点
Slow, slow, slow, slow.
转角  转角  转角
Corner, corner, corner.
对  抓着那头
Yeah. ‭Get that one.
你好  佩琪
Hi, Paige.
你还好吗
How are you?
是  哦不
Yeah, I mean, no.
没事的
No, it's fine.
什么
What?
可以啊
Well, yes.
当然可以  我理解
Of course. Right, I understand.
好的
Okay.
那真是太好了
Yeah, that would be perfect.
到时候再见  好的
I'll see you then. Great.
还有  佩琪  谢谢你
And, uh, listen, Paige, thank you.
谢谢
Thank you.
我
I, uh.
吉米
Jimmy.
什么  怎么了
What? What's up?
我
I, uh...
梅萨维德银行回来了
I just got Mesa Verde back.
-真的吗  -真的
- Seriously? ‭- Seriously.
-真棒  不敢置信  -就是啊
- Holy shit! That's unbelievable! - Yes.
我  那哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所怎么回事
I -- What happened to HHM?
佩琪没细说
Uh, Paige didn't go into it.
她只说文件没通过
She just said ‭the filing didn't go through.
我们今天下午见面
We're gonna meet this afternoon.
你看  我说吧
Hey, what did I tell you?
好人终有好报
Sometimes, the good guys win.
好像有些监管方面的问题
Oh, it sounds like ‭there's some regulatory issues.
凯文还是担心一个律师不能胜任
Kevin's still worried that one lawyer won't be able to handle it.
你可以的
You can.
我得请个律师助理  也许要两个
Yeah, I'm gonna have to get a paralegal, maybe two of them,
报酬肯定我一个人付
and I absolutely ‭will pay for it out of my end.
不  我俩平分报酬
No. Come on. Split it down the middle.
我得赶快弄个万律数据库终端
You know what? I need ‭a Westlaw terminal right away.
我都不知道这种事该打电话给谁
I don't even know who to call to get that done.
这都是高端的问题
These are high-class problems.
但这活儿可不小  吉米
Yeah, but it's a major piece of work, Jimmy.
很  很复杂
It's just -- It's -- It's -- This is major.
金  你可以的  好吗
Hey, Kim, you've got this, all right?
先缓一下
So take a moment. ‭
深呼吸  享受胜利
Breathe. Savor.
你说得对
You know what? You're right.
我当然对
Damn right I'm right.
是欧尼
It's Ernie.
欧尼  什么事
Hi, Ernie. What's up?
是的  没有  佩琪刚打电话给我
Yeah, no, Paige just called me.
查克说了为什么
Did Chuck say why --
那什么时候
So, when --
好的  现在去正好
Sure. ‭No time like the present.
好的  谢谢
Okay. Thanks.
梅萨维德的文件
The Mesa Verde files --
查克说可以给我了
Chuck's ready ‭to turn them to me.
真的
Really?
好快啊
That was... quick.
是啊
Yeah.
我换个衣服就过去
Uh, I'm gonna go change and get over there.
-需要帮忙吗  -看情况
- You want some help? ‭- That depends.
你是帮着搬箱子  还是在旁边幸灾乐祸
Are you gonna carry boxes, or you gonna gloat?
两个都要有一点吧
Uh, some from column "A," Some from column "B."
放个电
Ground yourself.
什么
W-- Sorry?
就碰一下那个东西
Just touch the thing.
怎么回事  开不开
What the hell? This thing doesn't...
-吉米你好  金你好  -欧尼你好
- Hey, Jimmy. Hey, Kim. - ‭Hey, Ernie.
锁出了点问题
Somethin's wrong with the lock.
麦吉尔让我打电话给锁匠换掉了
Mr. McGill had me call a locksmith and changed them.
是吗  为什么呢
Yeah? Why'd he do that?
查克  为什么要换锁
Hey, Chuck, why'd you change the locks?
欧内斯托  我这里没什么事了
Ernesto, I think we're good.
你肯定还要回办公室吧
I'm sure you're needed back at the office.
那我走了
Well... I'll get going, then.
-谢谢  -再见  吉米  再见  金
- Thanks. - ‭Bye, Jimmy. Bye, Kim.
-欧尼  再见  -回见
-Bye, Ernie. -See ya, Ernie.
那么  查克  锁怎么了
So, Chuck, ‭what's the deal with the locks?
金  本来这些话我想对你说
Kim, I was hoping to have this conversation with you
对你一个人说
and you alone.
但是
However...
我想现在该澄清所有事实了
I guess it's time to clear the air once and for all.
澄清什么事实
Clear the air about what?
他陷害了我
He sabotaged me.
兄弟  你说什么
Buddy, what are you, uh...
省省吧
Please. Don't bother.
你我都知道我要说什么
You and I both know ‭exactly what I'm talking about.
我不知道
I don't.
昨天早上是我职业生涯中最大的羞辱
Yesterday morning was the worst professional humiliation of my life.
一个小小的字序错误  浪费了委托人的
A single transpositional error cost my client time and money
钱和时间  永远破坏了我的名誉
and permanently damaged my reputation.
但我发现  不是错误
But then I realized... it wasn't an error.
根本不是
Not at all.
上一周的昨晚  我就睡在沙发上
A week ago last night, I was right there on that couch,
几乎失去了意识  吉米来了
barely consious, and Jimmy showed up.
支走了欧内斯托
and he sent Ernesto away.
我的好弟弟要亲自照顾我
My brother was gonna take care of me.
在夜深之时
And in the dead of night,
他翻了我的梅萨维德的文件
he went through my Mesa Verde files.
我们不用听你在这胡言乱语
Uh, you know what? We don't have to listen to this.
她得听
She does!
好好听  为你自己好
You do -- for your own good.
这里面有十三份文件
Now, in these files are 13 documents
标有梅萨维德银行拟设支行的地址
containing the address of Mesa Verde's proposed branch --
罗塞拉路1261号  亚利桑那州斯科茨代尔
1261 Rosella Drive, Scottsdale, arizona.
吉米抽出每一份文件
Jimmy pulled each and every one,
留我在这里大汗淋漓神志不清
then he left me here, sweating and delirious,
然后跑出去篡改了它们
while he went off to doctor them.
你需要复印机啊
You'd need a photocopier for that.
你去哪了  某个通宵营业的复印店吗
Where'd you go -- some all-night copy shop?
经过小心剪切和粘贴后
With a little careful cutting and pasting,
他做好了复制品
he created duplicates --
跟原件几乎一模一样
virtually identical to my originals,
只有一处关键差别
but with one key change --
罗塞拉路1261号成了罗塞拉路1216号
1261 Rosella Drive ‭became 1216 Rosella Drive.
这听起来可是大工程
This is sounding like a lot of work.
没人说你懒
No one ever accused you of being lazy --
你有各种缺点  唯独不懒
every other sin in the book, but not that one.
如果你想知道
And if you're wondering
吉米有没有能力伪造文书
if Jimmy's up to a little casual forgery,
那我告诉你
you should know in high school,
他高中时就曾靠伪造身份证日进斗金
he had a thriving business making fake I.Ds
让他的兄弟们都有啤酒喝
so his buddies could buy beer.
高中的事你也提吗
You going all the way back to high school, huh?
你跟莫扎特一样
Hey, you and Mozart, huh?
都是从小就有天分
You both started young.
他回来之后  便把复制品夹在我的文件里
He came back here and put his new versions in my files.
然后  第二天
And then, the next day,
我那体贴的弟弟就离开了
my caring brother took his leave.
他知道我会用他篡改过的文件
He knew that I would use his modified documents
撰写梅萨维德银行的申请报告
to write Mesa Verde's submission to the state regulator.
也确实如此  我一遍遍地
And so I did, over and over --
输入着1216  而不是1261
I typed "1216" instead of "1261."
我当时还想  "罗塞拉路1216
I remember thinking, "1216 Rosella Drive --
"是1215年的下一年
"that's just one year after 1215,
"是《大宪章》签署的第二年"
"the year the Magna Carta was signed."
天哪  查克  你疯了吧
Jesus, Chuck, you are unbelievable.
所以你的意思是  里面这些文件
So, you're saying, if we look in here,
上面的地址都是错误的
all the addresses will be wrong?
你当然不会留下证据
Well, of course you weren't gonna leave evidence behind.
我猜昨天早上  你等到我走了之后
I'm guessing yesterday morning, you waited until I left,
用你的钥匙进了门
then used your key to let yourself in
把原始文件还了回来
and return the originals.
没有掩盖的犯罪是不完整的
No crime is complete without the cover-up.
天哪拜托
Oh, come on.
我为什么要这么做  为了什么生意吗
I did all this -- what -- for some business?
他都是为了你
He did it for you.
你对此肯定一点都不知情
Oh, I'm sure you didn't know anything about it.
这肯定是他自己的主意
I believe he went off on his own
把这当成某种扭曲的浪漫之举
and did this as some kind of twisted romantic gesture.
查克  你应该躺下来
Chuck, ‭I think you need to lie down
用冷毛巾敷敷额头了
with a cold washcloth on your head.
现在你知道了  你别无选择了
And now that you know, you have no choice.
这事关委托人  一个被欺骗的委托人
This is about a client -- a client who has been defrauded.
作为一名宣过誓的律师
As a sworn officer of the court,
作为梅萨维德银行的正式代理律师
as Mesa Verde's attorney of record,
你只能去找凯文·沃弛泰尔
you have no recourse but to go to Kevin Wachtell
把这一切和盘托出
and make a full disclosure.
他这一整套说辞
This -- This whole song and dance --
只是为了夺回他的委托人
it's all about getting his client back.
-就是为了这个目的  -完全不是
- That's all this is. - ‭Not in the least.
如果他们得知真相后仍然决定...
If, knowing the truth, they still decide to go --
你不能忍受他们选择了她而不是你
You can't stand the fact that they chose her over you.
我不能忍受的是
I can't stand the fact
我的亲弟弟在我背后捅刀子
that my own brother stabbed me in the back!
我不能忍受你欺骗了这位年轻的女士
I can't stand the fact that you've deceived
-让她堕落至此  -"堕落"
- and ruined this fine young woman! - ‭"Ruined"?
现在是十九世纪四十年代吗
What is this -- the 1840s?
你说什么呢  她才没有堕落
What are you talking about? She's not ruined!
吉米
Jimmy.
如果你说的都是真的
If what you're saying is true,
吉米会被指控伪造文书  诈骗
Jimmy could be charged with forgery, fraud,
伪造证据  甚至非法侵入
falsifying evidence, even breaking and entering.
坦白说  我也很难受
Frankly, I am sick about this.
但事实就是事实
But facts are facts.
你有证据吗
And what is your evidence?
证据
My evidence?
证据就是我十分了解我的弟弟
My evidence is knowing my brother for his entire life.
查克  还有别的解释
Chuck, I think ‭there is another explanation --
一个更简单的解释
it's a simpler one.
你看错了
You made a mistake.
我没有
I did not.
你在油灯下工作
You're wororking by lantern,
眯着眼盯着那些打印出来的十磅小字
squinting over 10-point type for hour after hour.
错把1261当成了1216
Mistakenly changing 1261 to 1216
这是极其正常的事情
would be the most natural thing in the world.
我也可能犯这样的错
It could certainly happen to me.
我没有搞错
I did not make a mistake!
就是你搞错了
I believe you did.
我知道  你很喜欢吉米
Look, I understand that you have a -- a great affection for Jimmy.
很多人都喜欢  但请你睁开眼睛
A great many people do, but please open your eyes here!
你犯了一个错误  你非但不去面对它
You made a mistake, and instead of just facing up to it,
反而指责你的弟弟陷害你
you accuse your brother of plotting against you.
编造出这么精心策划的阴谋
You come up ‭with this elaborate scheme.
他做得出来
He's capable of this!
我知道他能
You know he is!
我知道他有很多缺点
I know he's not perfect!
我知道他喜欢走捷径
And I know he cuts corners.
但是你让他变成这样的
But you're the one who made him this way.
他崇拜你
He idolizes you.
他接受你
He accepts you.
他照顾你
He takes care of you.
他只想要你的爱与支持
And all he ever wanted was your love and support,
但你只会对他指手画脚
but all you've ever done is judge him.
你从来不相信他
You never believed in him.
你从来不希望他成功
You never wanted him to succeed.
你知道吗
And you know what?
我为他感到难过
I feel sorry for him.
也为你感到难过
And I feel sorry for you.
天啊  干什么
Jesus! What? ‭
金  干什么
Kim! What?
给我  开车
Just drive.
好了  根据班级排好队
All right, line up by class!
去找你们的小伙伴
Find your buddy!
孩子们  过来
Okay, kids, come on.
我们上
Let's go.
来  来
Come on. Come on.
-各就各位  -这边吗
- Plant yourself. ‭- All right. Here?
没错  这边
Yeah. Right there.
这么高就行了
About yea high. ‭
对准我  拍出英雄气概
Aim it up at me -- heroic.
英雄气概  祝你好运了
Heroic? Good luck with that.
赶紧给我拍
Just frame me up, all right?
把脖子也给化好
Make sure you get the neck, okay?
-这是从下方拍摄的  -好的
- It's a low-angle shoot. ‭- Okay.
算了  让我看看
Hey, you know what? Let me see.
这只是打个底
Oh, I-it's just base.
我这是得肺痨要死了吗
What -- am I dying of consumption?
你这个年龄段的人没那么红润
Well, at your age, ‭you don't want to look too red.
-应该有点红斑痤疮  -那这些...
- It looks like rosacea. - And what's with all the...
我只是想化出你下巴的轮廓
I'm just trying to make it look like you have a jawline.
我下巴本来就有轮廓
I do have a jawline.
这样吧  你站过去
You know what? You stand in for me.
蹲一点
Hey, crouch down.
往左  另一边
Okay. Move to your left. The other left.
再左一点  好了
More. More. Okay, boom!
就这样  懂了吧
That's what I'm talkinin about. You got it.
肯定还有更简单的拍摄方式
Oh, dude, there's got to be an easier way to get this shot.
免费的可没有
Not for free.
你要想拍电影  就得胆子大
You wanna be a filmmaker, grow a pair.
好了  准备正式拍摄
Here we go. Picture's up.
好  我们开始吧
All right, let's do this.
最后补一下
Last looks.
大黄  大黄  九点钟方向
Rhubarb, Rhubarb. 9:00.
不好意思
Excuse me.
你是这里的负责人吗
Hi. Are you in charge here?
是的  这是学校用地
Yes, I am, ‭and this is school property.
我正要找你呢
You're just the person I want to speak to.
如果你能让那幢楼里的孩子小声点
It would be incredibly helpful if you could get those kids in that building
会对我们很有帮助的
over there to just keep it down for a bit.
让他们做点练习之类的
Just give 'em a worksheet or something?
只要两三分钟  很快的
I mean, just two or three minutes, just for sound.
这里是学校用地
This is school property,
未经允许任何人都不得入内
and no one is allowed here without permission.
当然了
Of course not.
-安奈特没和你说吗  -安奈特是谁
- You didn't speak to Annette? - ‭Annette?
主管办公室的
In the Superintendent's office.
你认识城里叫安奈特的吗
Do you know an Annette downtown?
不认识
I don't think so.
抱歉添麻烦了
Well, I'm sorry about the mix-up.
我们在拍"定场镜头"
We're shooting what's called an establishing shot --
最多五分钟
five minutes, tops.
我弄清楚之前
You're not shooting anything
你们什么都不准拍
until I'm clear on what's going on here.
纪录片  我们在拍纪录片
The documentary -- we're making a documentary.
是...
That's -- Oh!
我听说有个展览或者纪念牌匾之类的
I was told there was a display or a plaque of some kind.
你知道在哪里吗
Would you know where that would be?
我们为什么会有牌匾
Why would we have a plaque?
因为曾在这里上过学的人
Because of who went to school here.
谁曾在这里上过学
Who went to school here?
鲁伯特·霍姆斯
Rupert Holmes.
就是关于他的纪录片
That's who the documentary is about.
抱歉  谁
I'm sorry. Who?
鲁伯特·霍姆斯
Rupert Holmes.
鲁伯特·霍姆斯  创作歌手
You know...Rupert Holmes, the singer/songwriter.
"椰林飘香之歌"
You know, um... "The Piña Colada Song."
一种鸡尾酒
你肯定知道  我...
I mean, sure you do. I...
如果你喜欢椰林飘香  被大雨困住*
*If you like piña coladas and getting caught in the rain
如果你不喜欢瑜伽  还算有点脑子*
*If you're not into yoga and you got half a brain
如果你喜欢半夜啪啪啪*
*If you like makin' love at midnight
在海角旁的沙丘*
*In the dunes by the cape...
知道吗  鲁...  看看她的脸
See? Ru-- Look at her face.
-鲁伯特·霍姆斯  -他在这上过学吗
- Rupert Holmes. - ‭He went to school here?
是啊  64届的
Yeah. Class of '64.
他现在还经常说
He still talks about it.
但这所学校是71年建的
But the school was built in '71.
他在那之前的老楼里上过学
Mm. He was a student in the old building that used to be here.
我们有点...怎么说呢
We're taking a little -- what do you call it?
艺术再创作
Artistic liberties.
鲁伯特·霍姆斯不是英国人吗
Isn't Rupert Holmes English?
是啊  这可以拿来做小趣事
Well, yeah, ‭and that's some great trivia,
但他青少年时期是在阿尔布开克度过的
but he spent his formative years right here in Albuquerque.
这样吧  你打到主管办公室
I'll tell you what -- why don't you call Annette
找安奈特
down in ‭the Superintendent's Office?
我们就在这等官方回话
And we'll just stay here till you get official word.
-好  如果你不介意等的话  -不会
- Well, ‭if you don't mind waiting. - Not at all.
我们不想违反任何规定
We don't want to break any rules.
不会太久的
Shouldn't take very long, I'm sure.
虽然不能保证
And no promises,
但我尽量让孩子们安静点
but I'll see what I can do about getting the kids to quiet down.
那真是帮了大忙了
Oh. ‭That would be super helpful.
快点  这时候正好
Chop-chop. Magic time.
-快点  -好的
- Come on, let's go. - All right
不做造型了  把旗子降下来
No last looks. ‭Just the flag -- the flag.
好  记着  英雄气概
Okay, remember -- heroic.
好  你是个英雄
Yeah, you're a hero.
-大英雄  -要庄重
- Big, big hero. - ‭Gravitas.
开始
Go.
推  推  推
Dolly, dolly, dolly.
漂亮
Nice.
阿尔布开克日报
-你好  麦克  -你好  弗兰
- Hey, Mike. ‭- Hey, Fran.
还供应早餐吗
You still serving breakfast?
你来就供应  老样子吗
For you? Sure. The usual?
好的
Um, be great.
谢谢
Thanks.
有什么好事吗
Anything good in the paper?
没有
No.
报纸上有过好事吗
Was there ever anything good in the paper?
确实不多
Not too often.
-弗兰  -怎么
- Hey, Fran. - ‭Yeah?
我问一下
I got to ask...
这里下过雪吗
does it ever snow around here?
下过
Sure, it does.
你要在阿尔布开克度过第一个冬天吗
This is gonna be your first winter in Albuquerque?
没错  我从费城来
Yeah. I'm out from Philadelphia.
看年份吧
Well, it depends on the year.
如果你待得够久
If you stay around long enough,
就会有雪铲的  不用担心
you'll have something to shovel -- don't you worry.
我喜欢铲雪
That suits me.
我住在锡达克雷斯特  经常下雪
I live up in Cedar Crest. We get plenty.
如果嫌不够可以来铲我家车道的雪
You can shovel my drive if you're looking for more.
一句话的事
Just say the word.
好吧
Yeah, well...
小姐  结账
Miss. check, please?
喂
Yeah.
我们得谈谈
We gotta talk.
我得知道些事
I've got something I need to know,
立刻告诉我
and I need to know it fast.
什么事
What's that?
我们不久前被抢了
We got hit the other day.
一辆向南开的卡车被劫了
A truck headed south got hijacked.
有人偷了二十五万
Someone stole a quarter million.
现在赫克托气疯了  在找是谁干的
Now Hector's flippin' out, lookin' for who did it.
问题是
Thing is...
我觉得是你
I think it was you.
司机被绑起来了  身上却没有伤痕
They left the driver hog-tied -- not a mark on him.
干这一行的都杀人不眨眼
Anyone in the game would capped him without a second thought.
但这个司机还活着
But this driver? He's still breathin'.
我就琢磨  这家伙是谁
I thought to myself, "who's the guy
抢了几十万毒资
who'll rip off a couple hundred thousand
还留一个目击者
in drug money and leave a witness?
什么人不愿开枪
Who's the guy ‭who won't pull the trigger?"
你
You.
我不是来勒索你的
I'm not here to squeeze you.
你想抢贩毒集团  那是你的事
You wanna rip off the cartel, that's your business.
但问题是
But here's the thing.
我要去接那个司机  赫克托的命令
I'm picking up that driver -- Hector's orders.
我们要看看他知道什么
We're gonna see what he knows,
如果他认出了你  对我俩都不好
and if he knows you, that's bad for both of us.
你不用担心
That shouldn't concern you.
但他跟你是一伙的  对吧
But he was in on it, right?
那司机和此事无关
The driver ‭had nothing to do with it.
-那是谁  -只有我
- Then who? - ‭Just me.
你是说你干这票  里头没人吗
You're telling me you did this without someone on the inside?
不可能
Not possible.
你怎么知道那辆卡车的
How did you know about the truck?
你怎么知道在轮胎里
How do you know about the tires?
要我说
All I can tell you is,
你们高估了自己的智商
you guys aren't half as smart as you think you are.
所以那个司机什么都不知道吗
So the driver... doesn't know anything?
-什么都不知道  -他听到你声音了吗
- Not a thing. - ‭He hear your voice?
-没有  -现在赫克托还在查竞争对手
- No. - ‭Right now, Hector's looking at the competition,
但他要是听司机说是个年纪大的美国佬...
but he hears the driver say it was some old gringo...
他没听到我说话
He didn't hear me.
他就看到一个戴滑雪面具的人而已
He saw a guy with a ski mask -- that's it.
你肯定
And you're sure of that?
没错
Yeah.
你最好别搞错
You better be right.
为什么没上报纸
Why wasn't it in the papers?
什么
What?
卡车劫案  警察没让上报纸吗
The truck robbery -- the cops keeping it out of the papers?
警察
The cops?
警察什么都不知道
The cops don't know shit about it.
怎么会呢
How's that?
这就是你的目的吗
Is that what this is about?
你想让警察去抓赫克托
You wanted to put the cops onto Hector?
为什么
Why?
你对他不重要
You are nothing to him.
他完全忘了你
He forgot all about you.
我可没忘记他
I haven't forgotten him.
你把我推进火坑
You put me in the shit,
就因为你想整赫克托·塞拉曼加
just 'cause you got it in for Hector Salamanca?
你把警察引向了他  也就引向了我
Listen, you put the cops on him, you put them on me.
你要是为了钱  我懂  但你这样
Doing it for the money -- I get it, but this shit --
真是疯了
that's insane.
你得冷静
You need to calm yourself down,
把手从口袋里拿出来
and you need to take that hand out of that pocket.
你要明白
Now, just so you know...
都结束了
it's over.
我跟你老板的事结束了
I'm done with your boss.
算了
Whatever.
为什么没上报纸
Why wasn't it in the papers?
因为我们收拾干净了
Because we cleaned it up.
怎么收拾的
How's that?
我们很幸运
We got lucky.
你离开后  有个好心人过来
After you left, ‭a Good Samaritan came along
大叫"天啊  天啊"
and said, "Oh, my God! Oh, my God!"
他给司机松绑  司机叫我们过去
He cut the driver loose. The driver called us.
我们过去开走了卡车
We came out, got the truck.
就好像没发生过一样
Made it like it never happened.
那好心人呢
And that Good Samaritan?
赫克托崩了他的脸
Hector shot him in the face.
我们把他埋在了沙漠里
We buried the guy out in the desert.
我说了...
Like I said...
我们收拾干净了
we cleaned it up.
你今天怎么样
How was your day?
跟佩奇和凯文见面
You know, met with Paige and Kevin,
面试了些律师助理
interviewed some paralegals...
还有这个
and, uh, this.
你呢
What about you? ‭
拍完了广告
Finished the commercial.
我不是卖弄  但这可能是
I don't want to oversell it, but I think it might be
电视史上最棒的六十秒
the greatest 60 seconds in the history of television.
明早
Tomorrow morning, uh,
11点18分到11点35分之间
somewhere between 11:18 and 11:35,
放下手中的活  转到《谋杀诊断》
stop what you're doing and tune in to "Diagnosis Murder."
美国电视剧
我记下来
I'll make a point of it.
你想谈谈这事吗
You want to talk about this?
现在不
Not now.
以后也不
Not ever.
我只想说...
I'm just gonna say...
你和梅萨维德是绝配
you are meant for Mesa Verde, and they are meant for you.
现在...一切都好了
So... all is right with the world.
晚安
Good night.
Night.
你哥是个聪明的律师
Your brother is one smart lawyer.
我认识的最聪明的  无意冒犯你
The smartest one I know -- I mean, no offense.
他会是强劲的对手
He'd make quite an adversary.
你说得没错
You'd better believe it.
他是那种
The kind of adversary
会发现你辩词中最细微漏洞的对手
who'd find even the smallest crack in your defense.
和他对抗  你真得确保
Going against him, you'd really want to make sure
你做得滴水不漏
you've got all your I's dotted and your T's crossed.
不留痕迹
Nothing for him to find.
二十四小时营业
你好吗
Hey, how ya doin'?
一会儿就来
Be with you in a minute.
记得我吗
Remember me?
不记得
Uh...no.
我觉得你应该记得  兰斯
I got a weird feeling you do, Lance.
今晚很有趣
Tonight is a funny night.
不知什么原因
For some reason tonight,
我感觉自己得到了全部答案
I feel like I've got all the answers...
感觉就好像
I'm feeling kind of like, uh...
卡纳克一样
like Carnac.
约翰尼·卡尔森在《约翰尼·卡尔森今夜秀》中出演的角色
你记得约翰尼·卡尔森过去演卡纳克吗
Do you remember when Johnny Carson used to do Carnac?
他会在问题提出前给出答案
You know, he'd give the answers before the questions.
埃德会给他信封  是吧
You know, Ed would give him the envelope, yeah?
约翰尼会将它顶住前额
And Johnny would hold it up to his forehead,
然后给出答案  比如
and, um, he'd give the answer, like,
"留给河狸"
"Leave It to Beaver."
上世纪五六十年代美国电视剧
然后约翰尼会打开信封
Then Johnny'd tear open the envelope.
问题是
And there's the question --
"浣熊的遗嘱里写了什么"
"What did the dead raccoon say in his will?"
想起来了吗
That ring a bell?
你那时没出生吗
Before your time?
我们言归正传
All right, well, let's cut to the chase.
刚走出这里的男人
Um, that guy ‭who just walked out of here --
名叫欧尼
his name is Ernie.
他给你看了我的照片吧
I'm guessing he showed you my picture
还问你我那晚来过这没有
and asked if ‭I was in here the other night.
他现在会带他老板来  也就是我哥哥
Now he's going to bring his boss, who's my brother,
他会问你同样的问题
and he's gonna ask you the same question --
"你那晚见过那人吗"
"Did you see that guy the other night?"
答案是没有
Well, the answer is no.
懂了吗
You feel me?
你杀人了吗
You murder someone?
没有
Nope.
抢银行了
Rob a bank?
我没那么厉害
No way am I that cool.
我有时候上大号不冲厕所  但...
I -- sometimes, I go number two and I don't flush, but...
这是兄弟间的事
this is just a thing between brothers.
而且我们都是律师  所以...
And we're both lawyers, so...
那是个冗长又无聊的故事
Right? I mean, ‭that's a long and boring story.
你没兴趣的
You don't wanna know.
这件事会惹来警察吗
Is this gonna get me jammed up with the cops?
我哥哥也许会跟你这么说  但是不会
My brotherer may make it sound like that, but...no.
家事而已
It's just family.
那我明白了
Then I feel you.
跟我说说摄像头怎么回事
Hey, ‭tell me about the cameras.
后面有台录像机
Oh. Uh, they go to a VCR in the back.
每录十二小时就回过头重录一遍
It, uh, tapes for 12 hours and then records over itself.
所以我现在被录上吗
Right. So I'm on there now?
要抹掉记录有多困难
How hard would it be to erase?
我不确定
Mm. I don't know.
可能很麻烦...
Could be tricky...
而且很贵
and expensive.
像一百块那么贵
Like 100 bucks expensive?
两百块那么贵
Like 200 bucks expensive.
你以后会大有作为的  年轻人
You will go far, my young friend.
晚上好
Uh, good evening.
兰斯  对吧
Uh, Lance, is it?
对
Yeah.
兰斯  我是查尔斯·麦吉尔
Lance, I'm Charles McGill.
我的助理之前找你谈过
Uh, my associate, uh, spoke with you earlier,
他给你看了这张照片
and he showed you this photo.
大约在十八号凌晨的时候
Um, on or about ‭the morning of the 18th,
这个人来过这里
this person was here in this shop --
对吗
is that correct?
大约在...
Uh. On or about the...
十八号  凌晨时分
The 18th, early morning.
没有
No.
你告诉我的助手
Well, I'm -- ‭I believe you told my associate
他来过这里  还复印了文件
that he was here and that he made copies.
是的  抱歉
Yeah, but sorry.
没来过
No.
好样的  这就对了
Yeah, that's my guy.
好吧  星期二  十七号的晚上
All right, the, uh, th-the night of Tuesday the 17th --
到星期三凌晨
leading into early Wednesday,
也就是十八号星期三凌晨
early hours ‭of Wednesday the 18th...
你当时在这里吗  这点能确定吗
...were you, in fact, here? Can we establish that?
我是上夜班的
Uh, I mean, ‭I work graveyard,
所以  是的
so, yeah.
坚持住  兰斯
Stay strong, Lance.
这个人来印过东西吗
Was this man here, making copies?
我刚说了没有
It's like I said -- I don't think so.
之前你说他来过
Well, earlier, ‭you said that he was here.
现在又说他没来过
Now you're saying that he wasn't here.
哪个才是真话
Which is it?
那个人给我看照片的时候
Yeah, well, when that guy showed me the picture,
我想  "也许吧"  可现在我再仔细一看
I thought, "Maybe," But now that I'm seeing it again, uh...
抱歉
Ah, sorry.
怎么说呢
Don't know what to tell you.
我应该看错了
Guess I was wrong.
孩子  仔细听着
Son, ‭listen carefully.
我是一名法庭工作人员  在调查一起重案
I am an officer of the court, investigating a felony.
这么说你是警察
So you're a cop?
不  我不是  我...  我...
N-No, I'm not. ‭I'm -- I'm -- I'm, uh, I'm --
麦吉尔先生  也许该送您回家了
Mr. McGill, ‭maybe we better get you home.
欧内斯托  别把我当小孩
Ernesto, do not speak to me as if I were a child.
我没事
I'm fine.
我不是警察
I am not a police officer.
我是一名律师
I am an attorney.
我在道义和法律上有责任
And I have a moral and legal obligation
把此事调查清楚
to get to the bottom of this matter.
调查清楚什么
The bottom of what?
伪造  欺诈  篡改证据
Forgery, fraud, falsifying evidence...
非法入侵
...breaking and entering.
这个人...他没事吧
This guy -- is he okay?
我正常得很
There's nothing wrong with me!
麦吉尔先生  也许我们可以
Mr. McGill, maybe we could
-休息一下  然后  -厄尼  闭嘴
- just take a break and -- - Ernie, shut up!
你仔细考虑自己说的话
You think about ‭the choice you're making.
我跟你说了他没来过
I already told you he wasn't here.
你还想让我说什么
What do you want me to say?
我想让你说出真相
I want you to speak the truth.
我知道他来过
I know he was here!
我知道他都干了什么
I know what he did!
把你和欧内斯托说的跟我说一遍
Tell me what you told Ernesto.
别再改变说辞了
Stop trying to change your story.
打扰一下  怎样改成11x14的
Excuse me. Sorry. How do we get this to do 11x14?
不好意思
No, excuse me!
我们正在说话呢
We are having a conversation here!
你得切换到第四托盘
You got to switch it to tray four.
我给你演示会更直观些  听着
It's easier if I show you. Look.
老兄  好了
Dude, okay.
我不想惹麻烦
I-I -- I-I don't want any problems here.
你快...把他带走
So, just... get him out of here,
不然我要报警了  好吗
or I'm gonna call the cops, okay?
别走  我们还没说完呢
Do not walk away from me! We are not finished here!
我已经和你说够了  老兄
I am done talking to you, man!
快报警
Call 911.
快报警啊
Call 911. Come on.